Rajesh

rajesh.mbcs12209@nfsu.ac.in 📞 9817366908 👂 Gurugram, Haryana

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/rajesh-y-93a108202

₽ Profile

Highly motivated, inquisitive and calm headed Information Security professional having strong ethics, values and expertise in identifying, assessing, and mitigating security risks across diverse domains. Possesses a logical approach to problem-solving, having excellent written, verbal communication, presentation skills and an effective collaborator.

Professional Experience

iRunway India 02/2024 - 02/2024 Associate Incident Response FTH Gurugram

Identifying, labeling and Capturing the PHI and PII

Cyber Secured India 04/2023 - 07/2023

Cyber Security and Digital Forensics Intern

Learning Cyber Security Concepts, performing Web Application and Mobile Penetration

Testing, learning basic Digital Forensics

Technovention at PGDAV College 03/2022 - 05/2022

'Content and Technical Head' New Delhi

Optimization both of UI/UX and Content. Also, Collaborating for content and presenting the ongoing developments.

D.H. Group Services for Myntra 06/2021 - 08/2021

Quality Checker

From working as normal Quality Checker then, promoted to third-Party Quality Checker.

Education

MBA in Cyber Security Management

National Forensic Sciences University, Gandhinagar(An Institute of National Importance) Networks, Cyber Security Governance, Risk Management, Auditing, Compliance and Security Testing. Digital Forensics, Mobile Forensics, Laws and Regulations, Cryptography and Blockchain, Incident Response, Documentation and Reporting, Cyber Security Frameworks and VAPT. Organizational Behavior and Communication

BSc Mathematical Sciences 2019 - 2022

PGDAV College, University of Delhi

Learnt Applied Statistics Concepts through out my Graduation.

Hands-on Excel and Advanced Numerical Python libraries such as Numpy, Pandas,

Matplotlib and Seaborn for Data Analytics and Visualization.

MySQL for Database Management and various other Mathematical and Statistical tools Operating System, Computer System Architecture, networks and programming.

2022 - 2024





Certificates

KPMG Certified Lean Six Sigma Green Belt holder ISEA Certified Cyber Hygiene Practitioner

IT Audit and Compliance Training by ControlCase

Fundamentals of Deep Learning

Certificate of Competency



Practical Security Controls Implementation within Network using Cisco Packet Tracer Lab

Present

Data Governance and Risk Management in usage of SPDI amidst DPDPA.

Creating a document to promote Data Governance cum Risk Management in usage of SPDI amidst DPDPA.

Comparative study of Mobile Forensics tools Cellebrite UFED and MOBILedit Express.

Create a plugin to generate Phishing Email using LLM